Finding Aid for the Richard P. Wunder Research Files, 1945-1989 MS.02
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
Richard P. Wunder Research Files
1945-1989
MS.02
The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives
39.0 Linear feet (74 boxes, 7 note card boxes, oversize material)
Research files of art historian Richard P. Wunder, containing artwork files, photographs, correspondence, writings and notes. Content mostly consists of his research on Gian Paolo Panini, though Hyacinthe Rigaud, Emmanuel Leutze, and architectural and theatre drawings are prominent topics as well.
Wunder, Richard P.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists mainly of Richard P. Wunder's research files on 18th century Italian painter and architect, Gian Paolo Panini, and George Van Derveer Gallenkamp's research files on French Baroque painter, Hyacinthe Rigaud. Wunder received the Rigaud material as a bequest from Gallenkamp. Materials on German-American history painter, Emmanuel Leutze, and architectural and theater drawings also figure prominently. These research topics stemmed from Wunder's personal scholarly interests and his career interests as a curator and director. Materials include correspondence, photographs, drafts, publications, and notes that relate to the creation of exhibits, lectures, catalogs, articles, and theses.
Provenance
Gift of Dr. Richard P. Wunder.
Access Restrictions
These records are open for research under the conditions of The Frick Collection/Frick Art Reference Library Archives access policy. Contact the Archives Department for further information at archives@frick.org.
Biographical Note
Richard P. Wunder, art historian, was born in Ardmore, Pennsylvania. He developed an interest in art while traveling with his mother in Europe. Wunder pursued this interest at Harvard, earning his bachelors, masters, and doctorate degrees in fine art. Between his studies, Wunder served in the army during WWII and the Korean War. After receiving his doctorate, Wunder became the Curator of Drawings and Prints at Cooper Union Museum, serving in this position from 1955-1964. He then went on to become the Curator of Painting and Sculpture for the National Collection of Fine Arts, Smithsonian from 1964-1968. Wunder returned to New York City as the Director for the Cooper-Hewitt Museum of Design from 1968-1970. During the 1970s, he taught at Middlebury College. He later became president of appraisals for Christie, Manson & Woods before retiring in 1990 to La Jolla, California. Richard Wunder died in 2002, at the age of 79.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in eight series. Each series represents a research subject area.
Series I: Gian Paolo Panini
Series II: Hyacinth Rigaud
Series III: Emmanuel Leutze
Series IV: Artist Files
Series V: Architectural Drawings
Series VI: Stage Set/Theater Drawings
Series VII: Other Drawings
Series VIII: Other Art Research
Gallenkamp, George Van Derveer, 1922-1980.; Leutze, Emanuel, 1816-1868.; Panini, Gian Paolo, 1691 or 2-1765.; Rigaud, Hyacinthe, 1659-1743.; Wunder, Richard P.; Art--Provenance--Research.; Artist files.; Correspondence.; Photographs.; Research notes.
- Series I: Gian Paolo Panini, 1948-1984, 11.0 Linear feet (23 boxes)
  Scope and Contents note
  The Panini material forms the bulk of Richard Wunder's research files. Wunder began his study of Panini--16th century Italian painter and architect--during his undergraduate career at Harvard. He completed theses about Panini for his bachelor and doctorate degrees, and maintained a lifelong interest in his work. This series consists mainly of artwork files that contain photographs and provenance information. Additionally, Wunder's writings on the topic of Panini, including his theses; correspondence regarding Panini; printed works regarding Panini; and notes and other research material are included.
  - Subseries 1: Artwork, circa 1948-1960
    The artwork files form the bulk of Wunder's research material on Panini. The files are subdivided into paintings, drawings, and engravings. Each folder contains a photograph of the artwork and a sheet listing the title, medium, size, owner, provenance, additional comments, and a photographer credit. Sometimes the folders include correspondence regarding attempts to obtain provenance information and/or photographs of the works.
    - Paintings
      Arrangement
      The paintings are arranged alphabetically by city, then specific collection, and then title. This information was gathered at the time of Wunder's research and may not reflect current painting locations.
      - Ajaccio (France), Musée des Beaux Arts -Ruins (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Algiers (Algeria), Musée des Beaux Arts -View of the Colosseum (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Amarillo (Texas), A. E. Khoury -Ruins (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Amiens (France), Musée de Picardie -Temple of Saturn, Lion Fountain, Preaching Man (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Ascoli Piceno (Italy), Pinacoteca -Ruins (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Avignon (France), Musée Calvet -Overgrown Ruins (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
      - Avignon (France), Palais des Papes (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
        8 Belisarius Series
        9 Death Leap of Marcus Curtius
        10 View of the Forum
      - Bagnères-de-Bigorre (France), Musée -Ruins, Cattle in Foreground (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Baltimore (Md.), Victor Frenkil -Column of Trajan, Pantheon, etc. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Baltimore (Md.), Victor Frenkil -Temple of Saturn, Colosseum, etc. (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Baltimore (Md.), Walters Art Gallery (Box 1, Folder 14-19)
        14 Alexander at the Tomb of Achilles
        15 Alexander Surprising Conspirators
        16 Colosseum Series
        17 Ruins, Baptism Scene
        18 Ruins, Christ Blessing Children
        19 View of the Forum
      - Barcelona (Spain), private collection (Box 1, Folder 20-22)
        20 Doric Ruins in a Landscape
        21 Ruins by a River
        22 Ruins with Conversing Soldiers
      - Barcelona (Spain), trade -Bearded Figure Addressing a Group, Circular Temple (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Barcelona (Spain), trade - Ruins, Vase, and Sibyl Addressing a Group (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Barnard Castle (England), Bowes Museum -Courtyard of a Palace (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Bath (England), Holburne Museum -Ruins,Ruins with a Circular Domed Rotunda (Box 1, Folder 26-28)
      - Berlin (Germany), Cassirert Helbing -Column of Trajan, Colosseum, etc. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Berlin (Germany), Graupes -Pyramid, Circular Temple (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Berlin (Germany), Graupes -Statue of Farnese Hercules, Sarcophagus, etc. (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Berlin (Germany), Lange's -Interior of S. Paolo Fuori le Mura (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Berlin (Germany), Lepke's (Box 1, Folder 33-37)
        33 Arcade with Belisarius Begging Alms
        34 Marriage at Cana
        35 Pool of Bethesda
        36 Ruins with Column of Trajan
        37 St. Paul Preaching to the Athenians
      - Berlin (Germany), Staatlichs Gemaldegalerie -Colosseum Series (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Béziers (France), Musée -Fanciful Arrangement of the Campo Vaccino (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Béziers (France), Musée -Fanciful Roman Town Square with Ruins (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Bloomfield Hills (Mich.), Cranbrook Academy of Art -Colosseum Series (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Bologna (Italy), Modiano Collection -Opening of the Porta Santa, St. Peter's (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Bologna (Italy), Podio Collection -Statue Near the Sea Shore (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Bologna (Italy), private collection -Arches of Argentine and Octavius (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Boston (Mass.), Boston Athenaeum -Interior of a Picture Gallery: Modern Rome,Interior of St. Peters (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Boston (Mass.), Museum of Fine Arts -The Trevi Fountain (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Boston (Mass.), Vose Galleries -Pool of Bethesda (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Bowhill (Scotland), Duke of Buccleuch -Interior of the Pantheon (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Bristol (England), Frost and Reed -The Pantheon and other Monuments (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Brooklyn (N.Y.), Brooklyn Museum (Box 1, Folder 50-53)
        50 Adoration of the Magi
        51 Adoration of the Shepherds
        52 Ruined Arch with Sarcophagus
        53 Vase, Arcade, Colosseum and Figures
      - Brussels (Belgium), Fienez -Mass of Ruins and Statuary (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - Brussels (Belgium), Baron A. Horstmann -Pyramid and Gate of Octavius, Landscape (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - Brussels (Belgium), Baron A. Horstmann -Temple of Sibyl, Landscape (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - Brussels (Belgium), Musée -Pantheon and other Ruins, Figure Preaching (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Budapest (Hungary), Museum of Fine Arts -Double Arcade, Figure Preaching (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Budapest (Hungary), Museum of Art -Ionic Colonnade, Vase and Archway (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Buenos Aires (Argentina), Mrs. P. de Koenigsberg -Colosseum Series (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Buenos Aires (Argentina), Mrs. P. de Koenigsberg -Pantheon and Other Monuments (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Buffalo (N.Y.), Albright Art Gallery -Festival of Montenero (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Buffalo (N.Y.), Aldred K. Warren -Port Scene with Figures (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Caen (France), Musée -Reception of the Blue Cord (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Cambridge (England), Fitzwilliam Museum -Death Leap of Marcus Curtius (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Cambridge (England), Fitzwilliam Museum -Ruins (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Cambridge (Mass.), Fogg Museum of Art -Adoration of the Magi (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Cambridge (Mass.), Fogg Museum of Art -Adoration of the Shepherds (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Carcassonne (France), Musée -Ruins, Figures Inspecting a Relief (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Carcassonne (France), Musée -Ruins with Figure Preaching (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Chicago Art Institute (Ill.) (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
        14 Arch of Janus, Soldiers
        15 Festival in Piazza Navona
        16 Pyramid and Pile of Ruins, Figures Conversing
      - Chicago (Ill.), W. Russell Button -Belisarius Begging Alms (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Columbia (S.C.), Museum of Art -Roman Monuments with Temple of Verpasian (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Compiègne (France), Musée Vivenel -Arch of Constantine and Doric Ruins (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Copenhagen (Denmark), King of Denmark -Arcade with Obelisk (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Copenhagen (Denmark), Statens Museum for Kunst -Interior of the Parthenon (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Culver City (Calif.), S. H. White -Death Leap of Marcus Curtius (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Detroit (Mich.), Institute of Arts (Box 2, Folder 23-26)
        23 Interior of St. Peter
        24 Ruined Arch, Statue, Water in Foreground
        25 View of the Forum
        26 View of the Forum and Colosseum
      - Douai (France), Musée -Ruins, Vase, Figures (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Douai (France), Musée -Ruins, Vase, Figure on Horseback (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Draguignan (France), Musée -Interior of St. Peters (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Dublin (Ireland), National Gallery (Box 2, Folder 30-34)
        30 Circular Temple, Pyramid, Preaching Man
        31 Colosseum Series
        32 Festival in Piazza Navona
        33 Vase, Archway, Group of Figures
        34 View of the Forum
      - Eagleskerry (England), Norman Colville -Festival in Piazza di Montecitorio (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Epinal (France), Musée -Arch of Drasus (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Escorial (Spain), Real Monasterio -Interior of Cardinal Valentis Gallery (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Escorial (Spain), Real Monasterio -Vestibule of St. Peters (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Florence (Italy), Bellesi -Alexander at the Tomb of Achilles (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Florence (Italy), Bellesi -Death Leap of Marcus Curtius (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Florence (Italy), Galleria Corsini -Archways with Statue of Centaur (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Florence (Italy), Galleria Corsini -Ruined Arcade Near Seaside (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Florence (Italy), M. Guidi Collection -Pantheon and Ruins (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Florence (Italy), trade -Arch of Constantine and Colosseum, Looking Toward the Forum (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Florence (Italy), Uffizi -Ruins and Statue of Dionysus (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Frankfort (Germany), Stadlichs Museum -Interior of a Roman Bath (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Frascati (Italy), Villa Falconieri -Decorations on a Corridor (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Gatchina (Russia), Castle -Arch and Vase Series (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Gatchina (Russia), Castle -Portico with Statue of Hercules and the Hydra (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Grand Rapids (Mich.), R. B. Baldwin -Ionic Ruins and Archway (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - La Granja (Spain), Palacio Real (Box 2, Folder 51-54)
        51 Christ Preaching in the Temple
        52 Cleansing of the Temple
        53 Pool of Bethesda
        54 The Stoning of Christ
      - Grenoble (France), Musée -Ruins, Pyramid, and Figure Preaching (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Grenoble (France), Musée -Vase, Basilica of Maxentaul, Figure Preaching (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Haddo House (Scotland), Aberdeenshire Collection -Interior of the Pantheon (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - The Hague (Netherlands), Nystadt -Cleansing of the Temple (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hamburg (Germany), Kunsthalle -Ruined Vaulted Archway (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Hamburg (Germany), R. Scholz-Forni -Pantheon Statue of Farnese Hercules, Pyramid (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Hannover (Germany), Landesgalerie -Interior of St. Peters (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Hannover (Germany), Landesgalerie -Water Festival in Piazza Navona (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Hartford (Conn.), Wadsworth Athenaeum -Interior of a Picture Gallery (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Hartford (Conn.), Wadsworth Athenaeum -View of Pisa (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Haverford (Penn.), Mrs. F. B. Hufnagel -Ruins (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Houston (Texas), Museum of Fine Arts -The Pantheon and Other Monuments (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Indianapolis (Ind.), Institute of Art -Colosseum Series (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Indianapolis (Ind.), John Herron Art Institute -Pantheon and Other Monuments (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Indianapolis (Ind.), John Herron Museum -Ruins with Temple of Artoninus and Faustina (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Kansas City (Kan.), Nelson Gallery of Art -Ruins, Soldiers Conversing (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Kansas City (Kan.), Nelson Gallery of Art -Ruins, Bearded Preacher (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Kingston (N.Y.), Fred J. Johnston -Vase, Ruined Portico, Belisarius Begging Alms (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Kress Collection -Interior of St. Peters (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Lausanne (France), Gevat -Soldiers at a Fort (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Leeds (England), City Art Gallery -Ruins with Figure of Belisarius (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Leeds (England), City Art Gallery -Terrace with Fountain and Ruins (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Leningrad (Russia), Hermitage Museum (Box 3, Folder 21-23)
        21 Corinthian Colonnade, Pantheon, Vase, Statue of Apollo
        22 Farnese Hercules, Colosseum, Temple of Castor and Pollux
        23 Pyramid, Lion Statue, Relief and Shepherds
      - Lexington (Va.), Washington and Lee University -Ruined Portico with Sarcophagus (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Lexington (Va.), Washington and Lee University -Burial of Lazzaroni (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Lille (France), Palais des Beaux Arts -Doric Ruins with Combat of Centaurs (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Lisbon (Portugal), Museo -Colosseum and other Monuments (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Liverpool (England), Walker Art Gallery -Pantheon Series (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - London (England), Apsley House (Box 3, Folder 29-31)
        29 Corinthian Portico, Statue, Preaching Man
        30 Festival in Piazza di Spagna
        31 Vase, Archway, Preaching Man
      - London (England), Art Collector's Association -Ruins, Shop, Figures on Horseback (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - London (England), Arthur Tooth and Co. (Box 3, Folder 33-40)
        33 Arcade and Preaching Figure
        34 Colosseum, Arch of Constantine
        35 Colosseum, Arch of Constantine
        36 Corinthian Structure, Pile of Ruins
        37 Hercules Slaying the Dragon
        38 Mass of Ruins, Standing Hermes
        39 Pile of Ruins with Amphitheater, Figures
        40 The Rape of Daenara
      - London (England), G. Belles -Mass of Ruins with Arch of Constantine (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - London (England), M. Bernard -Water Festival in Piazza Navona (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - London (England), Bridgewater House -Picture Gallery of Ancient Rome (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - London (England), Bridgewater House -Piazza S. Pietro with a Procession (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - London (England), Christies (Box 3, Folder 45-52)
        45 Classical Ruins
        46 Courtyard of a Palace
        47 Interior of the Pantheon
        48 The Marriage at Cana
        49 Piazza S. Pietro
        50 Ruins, Statue, Soldier
        51 Statue of Farnese Hercules and Theater of Marcellus
        52 Temple of Saturn and Baroque Building
      - London (England), Colnaghi (Box 3, Folder 53-56)
        53 Alexander and the Gordian Knot
        54 Mass of Roman Monuments
        55 Relief, Ionic Portico, Sphinx
        56 Relief, Vase and Pyramid
      - London (England), David Corrot -Ruins (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - London (England), R. Langston Douglas -Interior of St. Agnese in Agnone (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - London (England), R. Langston Douglas -Interior of St. Peter's, Loft Aisle (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - London (England), E. Duveen -Adoration of the Shepherds (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - London (England), Arthur Edwards -Ruined Column Structures (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - London (England), Fermoye -Pile of Ruins and Figures (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - London (England), Fosters -Doric Portico, Pyramid, Figure Preaching (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - London (England), Frost and Reed -View of Piazza del Popolo (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - London (England), Thomas Harns -Colosseum Series (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - London (England), Hazlitt Galleries -Ruins with Belisarius Begging Alms (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - London (England), Koetser Gallery -Interior of St. Peters (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - London (England), Koetser Galleries -M. Aurelius Statue, Pantheon and Ruins (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - London (England), J. Leger -Pantheon, Temple of Sibyl, Column of Trajan (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - London (England), Leger and Co. -Ruins with Statue of Marcus Aurelius (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - London (England), Leggat Bros. -Ionic Portico, Temple of Sibyl, Statue of M. Aurelius (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - London (England), Leggat Bros. -Roman Monuments (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - London (England), Levy Galleries -Roman Ruins with Statue of a Horse (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - London (England), M. Knoedler and Co. -Ruins with Belisarius Begging Alms (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - London (England), Matthiessen Galleries -Temple of Vespasian, Basilica of Maxentius (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - London (England), National Gallery -Interior of St. Peters (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - London (England), National Gallery -Statue Pyramid, Group of Figures (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - London (England), G. Neumans -Corinthian Archway, Statue of M. Aurelius (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - London (England), Dr. A. Scharf -View of the Forum (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - London (England), Spinks -Portico of Octavius, Colosseum etc. (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - London (England), Sotheby's (Box 4, Folder 24-26)
        24 Charles at Palace del Quirinale
        25 Ruins with Figure of Belisarius
        26 Throne and Revedos
      - London (England), Thomas Agnew and Sons -Cardinal York's Palace (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - London (England), Vicars Brothers -Ruins with Column of Trajan (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Longleat (England), Marquis of Bath -Interior of the Pantheon (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Los Angeles (Calif.), L.A. County Museum -Interior of St. Peters (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Louisville (Ky.), J.B. Speed Museum -Marriage at Cana (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Lucerne (Switzerland), Palace Hotel -Vase, Arch of Constantine and other Monuments (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Lyon (France), Musée -Ruined Arcade and Obelisk (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Madrid (Spain), Prado (Box 4, Folder 34-38)
        34 Christ Among the Doctors
        35 Cleansing of the Temple
        36 Pyramid, Statue, Figures, Water in Foreground
        37 Ruins with Circular Temple, Bearded Preacher
        38 Vase, Ruins, Sibyl Preaching
      - Mantoloking (N.J.), F. D. Callahan -Interior of S. Maria Maggiore (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Marseilles (France), Musée -Interior of a Picture Gallery (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Mexico City (Mexico), Museo Nacional des Artes Plasticas -Landscape, Ruins, a Bishop in Foreground (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Mexico City (Mexico), Museo Nacional des Artes Plasticas -Ruined Circular Structure with Shepherds (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Miami (Fla.), Robert Draper -Ruins with Preacher (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Milan (Italy), Dagoberta Paula -Pantheon, Colonnade, Obelisk, etc. (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Milan (Italy), Scopinichs -Calling of St. Matthew (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Milan (Italy), Scopinichs -Christ at the House of the Pharisee (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Milwaukee (Wis.), Art Institute -Ruins (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Montargis (France), Musée -Corinthian and Doric Ruins (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Montargis (France), Musée -Interior of a Roman Bath (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Montpellier (France), Musée Fabre -Arch of Titus, Pyramid, Pantheon (Box 4, Folder 50)
      - Montreal (Canada), Museum of Fine Arts -Ruins (Box 4, Folder 51)
      - Moscow (Russia), Rumantzeff Gallery -Figures in a Ruined Shack (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - Muncie (Ind.), Ball State Teachers College -Ruins with Bearded Preacher (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - Muncie (Ind.), Ball State Teachers College -Ruins with Female Figure Gesticulating (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Munich (Germany), E. F. Von Bissing Collection -Pool of Bethesda (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Munich (Germany), Depot -Courtyard with Ruined Arcade (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Munich (Germany), Galerie Heinemann -Arch of Janus Series (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Munich (Germany), Galerie Heinemann -Interior of St. Peters (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Munich (Germany), Schleissheim Gallery -Christ Curing the Paralytics (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - Munich (Germany), Schleissheim Gallery -Expulsion of the Money Changers from the Temple (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Nantes (France), Musée des Beaux Arts -Vase, Archway, Figure Preaching (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Naples (Italy), Canessas -Ruined Arch with Figures (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Naples (Italy), Museo Filangieri -Archway, Figure Preaching (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - Naples (Italy), Museo Nazionale (Box 4, Folder 64-68)
        64 Colosseum Series
        65 Ruins, Aged Satyr, Figure Gesticulating
        66 Vase, Ruins, Figures Examining Relief
        67 Charles III at Palace de Quirinale
        68 Charles III at St. Peters
      - Narbonne (France), Musée (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
        1 A Bacchanale
        2 Ruins of a Circular Colonnade
      - Nashville (Tenn.), Philip Kerrigan -Ruins (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - New Haven (Conn.), Yale University Art Gallery (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
        4 Colosseum with Figure Preaching
        5 Idealized View of the Forum
      - New London (Conn.), Lyman Allyn Museum -Interior of the Pantheon (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
      - New York (N.Y.), Acquavella Galleries -Ruined Archways; Truncated Obelisk and Ruins (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - New York (N.Y.), American Art Association (Box 5, Folder 9-13)
        9 Arch of Titus and the Forum
        10 Baroque Buildings at a Landing
        11 Baroque Palaces at Night
        12 Farnese Hercules, Colosseum, Pyramid
        13 Seaport with Ruins